<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd
http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ ">
    <responseDate>2025-06-28T15:26:33Z</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:pubmedcentral.nih.gov:12196004" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">
        https:/www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/oai/oai.cgi
    </request>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>oai:pubmedcentral.nih.gov:12196004</identifier>
                <datestamp>2025-06-26</datestamp>
                <setSpec>pathogens</setSpec>
                <setSpec>pmc-open</setSpec>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
                           xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                           xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                           xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
                    <dc:title>The Effects of High-Dose Probiotic Supplementation on Immune Activation and Neurocognitive
                        Disorders in People Living with HIV Undergoing Successful Antiretroviral Treatment: The Procog
                        Study
                    </dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Vassallo, Matteo</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Zerlini, Margaux</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Fabre, Roxane</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Joly, Heloise</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Durant, Jacques</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Makinson, Alain</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Mauries, Amandine</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Capeau, Jacqueline</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Fellahi, Soraya</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Bastard, Jean-Philippe</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Pradier, Christian</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Lebrun-Frenay, Christine</dc:creator>
                    <dc:source>Pathogens</dc:source>
                    <dc:subject>Article</dc:subject>
                    <dc:description>Background: The prevalence of HIV-associated neurocognitive disorders (HAND) remains
                        high despite antiretroviral treatment (ART). Changes in gut microbiota and persistent immune
                        activation have been suggested as possible causes, while the role of probiotic supplementation
                        remains controversial. Methods: We included subjects with mild HAND and successful ART. They
                        were randomized to receive either 6 months of high-dose probiotic supplementation or to continue
                        with only ART. Immune activation markers and neuropsychological testing were performed at
                        baseline and the end of follow-up. Neuropsychological testing assessed learning, episodic
                        memory, attention/concentration, executive functions, language, information processing speed,
                        and motor skills. Z- and T-scores were calculated for all domains but motor skills, allowing the
                        measurement of the global deficit score (GDS). The trajectories of neuropsychological
                        performances and immune activation markers were compared between groups. Results: From September
                        2020 to July 2021, 31 PWHs were included (median age 62, 73% men, CD4 744 cc/mm(3)), and 28
                        completed the 6-month follow-up. The characteristics of the subjects and their
                        neuropsychological performance at baseline in the two groups were similar. At the end of
                        follow-up, probiotics did not have any impact on immune activation markers, while they were
                        associated with better improvement in GDS (T-score 0.0 in controls vs. −0.3 in probiotics, p =
                        0.048) and the attention/concentration test (Z-score 0.4 in controls vs. 1.2 in probiotics, p =
                        0.035). Conclusions: Oral supplementation with high-dose probiotics for 6 months did not affect
                        systemic immune activation but was associated with improved neurocognitive performance,
                        suggesting benefits from probiotic supplementation for mild HAND.
                    </dc:description>
                    <dc:publisher>MDPI</dc:publisher>
                    <dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
                    <dc:identifier>/pmc/articles/PMC12196004/</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>/pubmed/40559576</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/pathogens14060568</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
                    <dc:language>en</dc:language>
                    <dc:rights>© 2025 by the authors.</dc:rights>
                    <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland. This
                        article is an open access article distributed under the terms and conditions of the Creative
                        Commons Attribution (CC BY) license (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).
                    </dc:rights>
                </oai_dc:dc>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>